So today we will talk about HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure.
We have made old videos of HDFC Agar Optima Secure
but some changes have come over
the time please.  So that's why we are bringing the revise video.
This video
is the latest video for HDFC Ergo Optima Secure
with revised benefits,
revised riders included.  So this
is a completely up to date video.
[Music]
Quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't already, please subscribe to our channel.
So that you get the right
infection at the right time.  Let's move on to the video.
HDFC Argo Optima Secure.  Before
starting about HDFC Ago Optima Secure, I
would like to tell you about HDFC Ago
's ICR which is Incurred Claim Ratio,
meaning how much amount the insurance company
collected and how much claim it paid.  So
ICR is 80.98%
as per the IRD report of last year and it keeps changing from time to time.  Let us move
ahead to the benefits of the policy.  We will
talk about its eligibility criteria and finally about the
premiums.  So if we talk about benefits, the first one is
room rent eligibility.
So there is no restriction on room rent eligibility in this policy.
You
can take as many rooms as you want.  So on this basis,
your actual health
insurance claim will be paid.  Minimum and maximum
entry age.  The minimum entry age is 18 years
for an adult.  And you can enter for the child on 91 days.
And there
is no entry age restriction for
adults only.  You can enter at any age you want.  Even if you are
80 years old,
you can still take this policy if you want to.   The
dependent age of the child is 24
years.  After 24 years the child will be
separated from the policy.  24 Completed
means after 25 years the policy will be
split from the child.  Will be put in a separate policy.
Now let's talk about sum
assured.  How much sum assured is available?   The
minimum is 5 lax.  Option available up to maximum Rs 2 crore.
Policy tenure: As
we discussed, one year, two year, three year
all three options are available.  If you take a two-year or
three-year policy together,
you are given some discount.  Because
you are paying the upfront premium to the
insurance company.  Here I will talk about
what is the difference between secure and super secure
?  Secure: As I told you, all
three options – one year, two year, three year –
are available in Secure.  But Super
Secure is a three year policy
only.  She is three years old.  You
can take a policy together.  What is the difference?  The
USP of this plan is that the coverage you get
is 2x the cover if you take Secured.  Meaning,
if you have taken a policy of 10 lakhs, then it will be
20 counts from day one.  If you have taken a policy of 50 lakhs then it will
count as 1 crore.  If you have
taken a policy of Rs 2 crore, then Rs 4 crore will be counted
from the first day.  And Optimize Super
Secure will be 3x count.  Meaning if there is a policy of Rs 50 lakh
then Rs 1.5 crore will be counted.
Whatever this is, it will be assured three times
from day one in Optima Super
Secure.  This policy is available only for three years.
So there is only a slight difference between Optima Secure which is 3 years
and Optima Super Secure three years
policy.   There
is very little difference.  But you are
getting one x additional cover if you are
going for Optima Super Secure.  So this
is the benefit of buying Optima Super Secure.
If you want to take a 3 year policy, then
instead of going for secure, go for
super secure so that your cover gets enhanced
by one X. You can move from secure to super secure
in future or you
can also move from super secure to secure pay
subject to underwriting guidelines. There is
another bonus in this which is plus
benefit loyalty addition. You are
continuing with HDFC Ergo. HDFC Ergo will add
50% to your policy next year and 50%
next year, which means 1X will be added
to your policy by the end of third year. So,
if you are taking a policy of Rs 10 lakh today.
Secure benefit means it will be worth Rs 20 lakh.
You are continuing it next year also.
Take 5 and it will be added.  If you are
continuing it next year also then 5
more will be added.  So after 3 years your
policy will be worth Rs 30 lakh.  The policy is worth Rs 10 lakh.
And this will not reduce.
Because this is a loyalty edition.  The plus benefit is
loyalty addition.  It is not claim based.  There
is no link to this on the claim.
This is Loyalty Edition.  Day care
hospitalization.  Day care procedures are those
where you do
not require 24-hour hospitalization.
Due to Advancement of Science and
Technology, even if you are admitted and discharged on the same
day, you still get the
claim.  Provided the line of
treatment is there.  There must be some line of treatment.  The
most common day care procedure
is catt.  Chemotherapy, dialysis, all these are
day care procedures.  And these are
covered in your policies up to the sum
insured.  Domiciliary hospitalization.
Domiciliary hospitalization
is also covered in your policies.  This is basically the hospitalization where
you are getting hospitalized at home.
Why?  Because firstly there are
no beds available in hospitals.  The second patient
is so critical that he cannot go to the hospital.  So
day care and domiciliary hospitalization
are also covered for you.  Then comes Ayush
hospitalization.  Hospitalization related to Ayush Ayida, Yoga,
Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy
is also covered in your policy, up to sum in short.  Then comes the
restore benefit.  Now
what is the restore benefit?  Restore Benefit is that if your
base sum assured, secure benefit plus
benefit is exhausted.  Once utilized
in any year, the company will
restore it in your policy once a year.
What will it restore?  Base sum assured for which
you have paid the premium.  So if
you paid a premium of Rs 10 lakh, then Rs 10 lakh
is your base.  If you pay a premium of Rs 50 then
50 lakh is your base.  Then the base sum assured will be
restored again.  Once in a
policy year and you can
use it for anything.  You can use up to base sum assured in the policy anytime for same illness, for
different illness, for same person, for
different person.
And if you want to convert this into unlimited restore
once a year, it
is built into the policy.  If you want to convert this into unlimited restore, then
you can convert it into unlimited restore by paying a little additional premium.  And
you will enjoy unlimited restore benefits.
Every time whenever it ends, ₹1
lakh will be refilled.
Emergency Road Ambulance for Different Hospitalizations.
If you use a road ambulance
to reach the hospital, it is covered
up to the sum insured.  Meaning whatever actual
expenses will be incurred will be paid.  Emergency air
ambulance is also covered.  Wherever domestic
evacuation is required through air
ambulance.  There the company will cover expenses up to Rs 5 lakh.
Complimentary Wellness
Test: The company also provides you complimentary preventive health checkup in your policy
so that you can take care of your health
and if there is any
deviation in your reports, you can take corrective action
timely.  So prevention is better than
cure.  So the company also believes in it.
So we give you preventive health checkup
once a year.  Its limit
is specified.  You can claim up to Rs 15,000.
Depends on your sum assured
and policy type.  Individual limits
are different.  Family floater is different.
You can check the policy you are taking.  The
maximum limit is Rs 15,000 which
you can currently avail on reimbursement basis.
You can also get reimbursed pre and post hospitalization expenses i.e. expenses incurred before and after going to the hospital.
Pre-hospitalization expenses
are 60 days post which you can get reimbursed for 180 days.
E-Consultation.  E-consultation
is included in your policy for listed
51 critical illnesses.  For that you
can e-consult their doctors.
Modern Treatments and Robotic Surgeries.
Your modern treatments and robotic
surgeries are covered up to sum assured.  Non-
payable items which we
also call consumable items.  Like PPE kits, masks,
gloves, these are also covered in your policy.   There is an
inbuilt protect benefit that
you can avail and also assures that
your non-payable items are covered.  Copayment There
is no copayment of any kind in this policy.  The insurance company pays 100% claim.
Voluntary deductible.  If
you want, you can pay a small initial amount.  On
top of that, you can choose the insurance company which is the
annual aggregate deductible.
What happens in return?  The insurance company
gives you a discount.  For example, you have a
policy of Rs 10 lakh.  X was your premium.
You chose a deductible of 25,000.  Now
your premium will be reduced by 25%.  You will have to
pay 25% less because you have
agreed that you will pay the first Rs 25,000 claim
and this has to be paid only once a year.
So this is annual aggregate deductible.   If you
want to understand in detail
what copayment deductible is, then
you will find its video in the link below.  Deductible
is available. Deductible ranging from Rs 25,000 to Rs 5 lakh
is also available.  Suppose you have a
policy running somewhere else.  A policy of Rs 3 lakh to Rs 5 lakh is
running.  If you want to take this policy on top of that then
definitely take it.  Firstly,
you will be able to enjoy its benefits.   The
premium will be lower as there
is a higher deductible and you will be enrolled in Optima Secure.
So it is your choice.  This
deductible may be removed in the future.
But there are some restrictions for that.  Please do get that
through.  There is an easy switch option
which you can enable and you can
enable it before 61 years.  Can't do it after that.
After these five years you
can enable the easy switch option.  Meaning, today
you took a policy with a deductible.  If
you wish to remove the policy after 5 years, you can
avail the easy switch option subject to underwriting.
Deductible can be removed.
But if you cross the age of 61, you will
not get the easy switch option.  You cannot remove it.  The
gift is OPD cover.  So this
is optional cover.  You can also get OPD
covered in your policies which is called
Optima Well Being Rider.  So,
as you can see on the screen at Optima Well Being, the in-
person consultations that you
can do with the doctor are
included, unlimited with general
practitioners.  Then
you can also do teleconsultation with general practitioners and routine
specialists.  You can take unlimited online fitness classes
through their partner network.
You can avail all these things through HDFC Ago HR app.
Home sample
collection is free for you.  You will have to pay the cost of the test.
You can also consult e-wellness
for mental health, diet
and nutrition and you
also get discounts on your lab tests and medicines
if you book through the app.
You can add this rider.  There is an optional rider.
Individual is also added.  This
family floater also gets added.  Now let's talk about
waiting periods,
what are the waiting periods in this plan?   The
initial waiting period is 30 days.
Plant hospitalization is not covered for the first 30 days.
Then after that there is a specific
exclusion waiting period.  Which are slow
growing illnesses.  The list of slow growing illnesses is in
front of you.  There are some diseases
which are not covered for 24 months i.e. two years.  There
is a standard waiting period.  As you can see in this list, the
names of the illnesses are given and the surgical
procedures are also given.  Illnesses include
internal congeneric diseases, non-infectious
arthritis, pancreatitis,
tonsillitis, sinusitis.  You can see
fibroids
come under prostate surgical procedures.  Your
tonsillectomy, adenoid removal
surgery, hernia, piles
, fibroid removal surgery, knee
replacement surgery, cataract surgery, all these
are excluded for two years.  So
if you need these things after one year from LETS
, then the insurance
company will not give them.  Because it comes under
waiting period for two years.  Then we come to the
waiting period of pre-existing conditions.
Pre-existing diseases are
not covered for three years.  Pre-
existing diseases such as any
medicines you take on a regular basis.
In case of pre-existing diseases, it is important to disclose any surgical history or past hospitalization.
We have made a lot of videos.  Don't forget to also see
what pre-existing illnesses cover and
why it is important to disclose them.
We are sharing its link.  We will move
ahead.  We will talk about riders and
which optional riders
are available that you can choose in the policy.   The
first one is the Unlimited Restore Rider,
which I told you is
available once a year, you can convert it into Unlimited
by opting for
Unlimited Restore Rider.  The second is Daily
Hospital Cash.  If you have taken hospital cash
benefit, what will you get in it
?  ₹2000 maximum you can choose from the
plans that are available.  Daily you will get
a reimbursement of ₹2000
for the number of days hospitalized.
Suppose someone is hospitalized for five days
and he has taken the hospital cash add-on,
then for those five days
you can get a separate reimbursement of ₹2000 per day * ₹5,100.
Then comes
IPA IPA is individual personal
accidental.  So basically you can add on your
accidental death, permanent disability,
permanent total, permanent partial
disability in this policy
which will be covered.  Then there is
Optima Well Being which is the OPD rider
that we talked about.  All these
are optional.  You will have to pay add-on premium.  Then there
is critical illness.  Now
you will ask that critical illness is
not covered in the policy.  Yes, everything from
hospitalization for critical illness,
accident etc. is covered in your policy.  But the
advantage of taking a separate add-on is that you
get a lump sum benefit if any critical
illness is diagnosed.  Different plans are available in this.
You can get cover from seven illnesses to 51 illnesses.
Here is the list on the screen in front of you.
If these 51 illnesses occur then lump sum payout will be given.
For example, you have taken a policy of Rs 50 lakh
and you have
also taken a CI rider of Rs 20 lakh.  Critical illness
rider is also taken.  Cancer is
diagnosed through LETS.  So, the
hospitalization expenses of cancer, chemotherapy
, medicine cost, during
hospitalization will be covered
from 50 lakh cover.  And the Rs
20 lakh that was to be given on diagnosis will be given in full.
Whatever hospital bill comes, it will be settled.
But if cancer is covered in your CI rider of Rs
20 lakh separately, then
one time payment will be made which
is lump sum payment.  So as per this list,
you can see that you can
cover from seven to 51 illnesses by
paying additional premium.  Limitless Rider.
So, limitless basically means that
whatever your claim amount is, the entire
amount will be paid irrespective of your sum
assured in the policy.  If you take this rider,
suppose you have a policy of Rs 10 lakh and you
take a limitless rider and a claim of
Rs 50 lakh comes, then the insurance company will pay it.
So the Limitless Rider is for those who do
n't want to worry about the sum assured.
They can choose the
limitless rider so that they can get the full amount of the claim.
Next is the ABC D
Chronic Care add on.  This news add on was
introduced some time back where
we cover A B C D which is Asthma, BP,
Cholesterol and Diabetes in your policies from
day one.  Where there was a
waiting period of three years, there will be no
waiting period of three years under these conditions.
You can get these on day one
by opting for ABCD riders.  So
if you want to bring these conditions on day one then
you can choose ABCD rider.
And these conditions will be covered from your day one.  Then There Is
Parenthood which
covers your maternity costs.  If you want
maternity which was not covered in HDFC Ergo Plus earlier.
Now this rider has been
introduced where you can also cover maternity costs.
If you feel that you may
need maternity benefits in the future,
you can opt for a paternity rider.  It comes
with a waiting period of two years.
You can cancel it after two years.  And there
are four options available in it.  50000, 1
lakh, 1,5000 and 2 lakh.  Whichever option you choose, it is a
fixed benefit that you will
get the same cost on delivery.  The
premium will be charged according to the benefit you avail.
In maternity, all three of your prenatal, postnatal and maternity
costs are covered.  Up to the
limit specified.  If you are taking Rs 5,000 then
all the things will be covered in Rs 5,000.
Pre-expenses, post-
expenses and also delivery costs.
Along with maternity, you can also get IVF covered
and the cost of embryo freezing covered.
But remember the cost will be Rs
50,000, Rs 1,150 or Rs 2 lakh.  The
maximum cover will be based on the benefit you avail.  I have
taken 2 lakhs.  Whether you get delivery done in it
, whether you get IVF done in it
, or get embryo freezing done.   You
can claim anything, prenatal, postnatal.  With an initial waiting period of
24 months.  You can make this claim after 24 months.
And last but not the least rider is
your deductible.  Consider this rider as an add-
on which reduces your cost.
Where we have talked about it before.
You can avail annual aggregate deductible.
From Rs 25,000 to Rs 5 lakh.
What will happen if you take this deductible?  Your premium cost will
reduce.  But you will have to pay this deductible amount
to the hospital at the time of claim.
Suppose you have taken a deductible of ₹2,000
and the claim comes to ₹5 lakh.  Now the
insurance company will not pay the full claim of Rs 5 lakh.
You will give ₹25,000.  The
insurance company will pay Rs 4,75,000.  If a
claim comes again in the same year, then she will make all the claims
to the insurance company.
You have to pay Rs 25,000 only in the first claim.  So these
were the policy details of HDFC Ergo Optima Secure along with recent
add-ons and recent features.
In the end, I had
told you that I will share the premium.  Premium
details are below.  Optima Secure Key as well
as Optima Super Secure Key.  You
can see.  And I have also added a deductible option.
So that you can see
how much difference the deductible makes to the actual premium.
And
choose according to your needs.  A quick
reminder that your due diligence is also important.
Before taking any policy.  So make
sure to do your due diligence and only then
buy a policy.  Want to connect
, want to connect with our team,
want to buy our through policy.
Contact number and communication details are
shared below.  you can call.  You
can email us or fill out the Google form.
Our team will connect you.   You
can also do WhatsApp.  So and if you have any
feedback, please share it in the comment section.
And if you have any questions, please tell me that too.
We will try our best to answer them.
Quick reminder before we go, if
you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so.
So that you get the
right infection at the right time.  See you
in the next video.  Till then stay safe, take
care.  Bye-bye.  Come